Guide to the Reference Center for Marxist Studies Pamphlet Collection PE.043
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- U.S.S.R.: Laws (19 pamphlets) (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Korshunov, Yuri. Soviet Law on Teenage Labour. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., undated (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Love - Family Life - Career. Woman Today Publishing Company, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Plotkin, M. A. Legal Status of Foreigners in the USSR. USSR Chamber of Commerce, Moscow., 1934 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - The Rights of Factory and Office Trade Union Committees. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1971 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - The Labor Laws of Soviet Russia. The Russian Soviet Government Bureau, New York, NY., 1920 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - The Marriage Laws of Soviet Russia. The Russian Soviet Government Bureau, New York, NY., 1921 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - The Soviet Law on Marriage. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1933 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Vyshinsky, A. Y. The Soviet Electoral Law: Questions and Answers. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1955 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Yevteyev, M. and V. Kirin. New Soviet Legislation to Combat Crime. Progress Publishers, Moscow., 1973 (Box 111, Folder 1)
- U.S.S.R.: National Question (8 pamphlets) (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Bagramov, E. The CPSU's Nationalities Policy: Truth and Lies. Progress Publishers, Moscow., 1988 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Chekalin, M. The National Question in the Soviet Union. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1941 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Dunayeva, E. A. The Collaboration of Nations in the U.S.S.R. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1952 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - How the Soviet Government Solves the National Question. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the USSR, Moscow., 1923 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - The National Question in the USSR: History and Our Time (articles from Communist, a theoretical and politial journal published by CPSU Central Committee). Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1989 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - The Nationalities Question: How it Was Solved in the USSR. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1972 (Box 111, Folder 2)
- U.S.S.R.: Peace I (19 pamphlets as well as brochures) (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Andropov, Yuri. Our Aim Is to Preserve Peace. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1983 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Beria, Laurenti P. The Soviet Union Builds for Peace. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1952 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Clark, Joseph. Who Wants War? How the Soviet Union Builds for Peace. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1951 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Davies, Hon. Joseph E. Our Soviet Ally in War and Peace. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1944 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Let Us Strengthen the Unity of the Communist Movement for the Triumph of Peace and Socialism. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1963 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Litvinoff, M. The Soviet Union Stands for Peace. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1932 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Proposals on Germany and Berlin. Soviet Booklets, London., undated (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Stalin, Joseph and V. M. Molotov. The Soviet Union and World Peace. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1946 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Strong, Anna Louise. The Soviet Union and World Peace. International Pamphlets, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1935 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - The Fifth Anniversary of the INF Treaty. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1989 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Troyanovsky, Alexander A. For World Peace and Freedom. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc. (2 copies), 1943 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - "We Stand for Peaceful Coexistence" Interviews with N.S. Khrushchev N.A. Bulganin G.K. Zhukov. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1955 (Box 111, Folder 3)
- U.S.S.R.: Peace II (16 pamphlets and an article) (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - A Peace Treaty with Germany: Three Speeches by N. S. Khrushchev. Crosscurrents Press, New York, NY., 1961 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Kalinin, Mikhail. World Peace or War?. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Litvinov, M. M. The U.S.S.R.: A Powerful Bulwark of Universal Peace. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1937 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Molotov, V. M. The Plan of Construction and Peace. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1936 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Molotov, V. M. The Soviet Union and the Peace Front. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1939 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - To the Peoples of the World. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1972 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Tukhachevsky, M. N. Sentinel of Peace. International Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1936 (Box 111, Folder 4)
- U.S.S.R.: Perestroika (5 pamphlets) (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Gorbachev, Mikhail. Perestroika Is the Concern of All Soviet Peoples. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1989 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Gorbachev, Mikhail. The Party of the Revolution Is the Party of the Perestroika. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1987 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Moiseyev, Nikita. Perestroika as Seen by a Mathematician. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1989 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Perestroika Who's Against. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1988 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - The Necessity for Change Perestroika and the Trade Unions. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1989 (Box 111, Folder 5)
- U.S.S.R.: Red Army (6 pamphlets) (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Alfred, A. The Red Army. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Moiseyev, Mikhail. The Soviet Military Doctrine: Orientation Towards Defense. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1989 (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Montagu, Ivor. The Red Army at War: 50 Questions Answered. Evans, Spencer and Co., London., 1943 (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - The Red Army. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1941 (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Voroshilov, K. E. Stalin and the Red Army. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1937 (Box 111, Folder 6)
- U.S.S.R.: Red Day (1 pamphlet) (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - International Red Day. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1929 (Box 111, Folder 6)
- U.S.S.R.: Republics I (17 pamphlets) (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - U.S.S.R.: Republics I (Box 112, Folder 1)
- U.S.S.R.: Republics II (17 pamphlets) (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - U.S.S.R.: Republics II (Box 112, Folder 2)
- U.S.S.R.: Science (8 pamphlets) (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - U.S.S.R.: Science (Box 112, Folder 3)
- U.S.S.R.: Socialism and Development I (15 pamphlets) (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Foster, Wm. Z. Victorious Socialist Construction in the Soviet Union. Trade Union Unity League, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Lamont, Corliss. Socialist Planning in Soviet Russia. Friends of the Soviet Union, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Manuilsky, D. Z. The Results of Socialist Construction in the U.S.S.R. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1935 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Molotov, V. The New Phase in the Soviet Union. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Platt, Leon. Building Socialism in the Soviet Union. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Stalin, Joseph. From Socialism to Communism in the Soviet Union. International Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Strong, Anna Louise. What About Russia?: An Honest Reply to Honest Questions. American Friends of the Soviet Union, New York, NY., undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Tikhomirov, W. A. Co-operatives in Socialist Construction. Published by the author., 1927 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Yudin, P. F. The Nature of Soviet Society. International Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1951 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Yudin, P. F. The Prime Source of the Development of Soviet Society. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1950 (Box 112, Folder 4)
- U.S.S.R.: Socialism and Development II (22 pamphlets) (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Ambartsumov, Evgeni; Burlatsky, Fyodor; Krasin, Yuri and Erik Pletnyov. Against Distortion of the Experience of Real, Existing Socialism. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1979 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Dunn, Robert W. and George Wallace. Life and Labor in the Soviet Union. International Pamphlets, New York, NY., 1937 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Khrushchev, N. S. The Socialist Way. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1960 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Krylenko, N. Safe-Guarding Public Socialist Property., undated (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Manuilsky, D. Z. The Rise of Socialism in the Soviet Union. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Mikulina, E. Socialist Competition of the Masses. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the USSR, Moscow. (2 copies), 1932 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Rust, W. 24 Years of Soviet Power. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1941 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Socialist Competition in the Soviet Union. Friends of the Soviet Union, New York, NY., undated (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Soule, George. Does Socialism Work?. New Republic, Inc., New York, NY., 1936 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Turner, James B. Socialism Marches On in the Soviet Union. International Pamphlets, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1937 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Vasetsky, Nokolai. Misinterpretations of the Historical Experience of the October Socialist Revolution. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1987 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Webb, Syndey and Beatrice. Is Soviet Communism a New Civilization?. The Left Review, London. (2 copies), undated (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Webb, Sydney and Beatrice. Soviet Communism: Dictatorship or Democracy?. The Left Review, London., 1936 (Box 112, Folder 5)
- U.S.S.R.: Soviet Society (10 pamphlets and a brochure) (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Antonov, Alexander. Work and Wages the Soviet Way. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Chernenko, K. Soviet Democracy: Principles and Practice. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1977 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Dedul, Alexander. Social Security in the USSR. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1985 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Kalinin, M. I. What Soviet Government Has Done for the Working People. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Lykova, Lidia. Social Security in the USSR. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Mstislavsky, P. Living Standards in the U.S.S.R. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY., 1964 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Shirvindt, E. Russian Prisons. International Class War Prisoners' Aid, London., undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Shtylko, Anatoly. 108,000,000 New Tenants. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Zverev, A. G. The Soviet Standard of Living: Social Benefits. International Arts and Sciences Press, New York., 1959 (Box 113, Folder 1)
- U.S.S.R.: Trade (7 pamphlets) (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Alexandrov, M. International Trade and the Improvement of the Standard of Living in the West. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1952 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - McAvoy, Clifford T. The Trade Unions of Our Soviet Ally. The American Council on Soviet Relations, New York, NY., 1942 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Morgan, Thomas A. Trade with Soviet Russia., 1932 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Soviet 'Dumping' and 'Forced Labor'. Friends of the Soviet Union, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - "Soviet Dumping" Fable. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 113, Folder 2)
- U.S.S.R.: Trade Unions I (14 pamphlets) (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Avdeyeva, K. The Trade Unions and Socialist Construction in the U.S.S.R. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1929 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Foster, William Z. The Soviet Trade Unions and Allied Labor Unity. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1943 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Lozovsky (Dridzo), A. The Role of the Labor Unions in the Russian Revolution. The Union Publishing Association, New York, NY., undated (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Phillips, Jack. Soviet Trade Unions. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1988 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Shvernik, J. Trade Unions Under Socialism. R.I.L.U Publications, London., 1932 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Edwin S. Organized Labor in the Soviet Union. National Council of American Soviet Friendship, New York, NY. (3 copies, different versions), 1943, 1944 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - The Soviet Workers and Their Unions: Questions and Answers. National Council of American Soviet Friendship, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1952 (Box 113, Folder 3)
- U.S.S.R.: Trade Unions II (15 pamphlets) (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Abolin, A. The October Revolution and the Trade Unions. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1933 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Allen, Charles R. Jr. Journey to the Soviet Trade Unions. Marzani and Munsell, New York, NY., 1965 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Losovsky, A. The Third All-Russian Congress of Trade Unions. All-Russian Central Council of Trade Unions, Moscow., 1920 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Lozovzky, A. (S. A. Dridzo). The Trade Unions in Soviet Russia. All-Russia Central Council of Trade Unions, Moscow., 1920 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Trade Unions in Soviet Russia. The Rand School of Social Science, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1920 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Zinoviev, G. The Communist Party and Industrial Unionism. The Workers' Socialist Federation, London., undated (Box 113, Folder 4)
- U.S.S.R.: Trials (12 pamphlets) (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Carr, Sam. From Opposition to Assassination. Central Committee, Communist Party of Canada, Toronto., undated (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Foster, William Z. Questions and Answers on the Piatakov-Radek Trial. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1937 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Letter of an Old Bolshevik: The Key to the Moscow Trials. Rand School Press, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1937 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Pritt, D. N. At the Moscow Trial. Soviet Russia Today and International Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies, different versions), 1937 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Traitors Accused: Indictment of the Piatakov-Radek Trotskyite Group. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1937 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Trial of American U-2 Spy Pilot. Soviet Booklets, London., 1960 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Yaroslavsky, E. The Meaning of the Soviet Trials. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1938 (Box 113, Folder 5)
- U.S.S.R.: U.S.A. Relations (28 pamphlets and an article) (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Since Sputnik: How Americans View the Soviet Union. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1959 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Arbatov, Georgi. The Dream World of American Policy. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1982 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Davies, Joseph E. The American-Anglo-Soviet Alliance. The American Council on Soviet Relations, New York, NY., undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Foster, William Z. The Soviet Union: Friend and Ally of the American People. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1941 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Foster, William Z. The United States and the Soviet Union. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (4 copies), 1940 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Foster, William Z. The U.S.A. and the U.S.S.R.: War Allies and Friends. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1942 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Geneva the Soviet-US Summit. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1985 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Hall, Gus. The Big Stakes of Detente. New Outlook Publishers, New York, NY., 1974 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Hall, Gus. The Only Choice Peaceful Coexistence. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1963 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Hall, Gus. The Struggle for Detente., undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Kozlov, Frol R. The Development of Economic and Cultural Cooperation -- An Important Factor in Strengthening Friendship Between the Soviet and American Peoples. International Arts and Sciences Press, New York, NY., 1959 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Lamont, Corliss. America and Russia. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1943 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Robins, Col. Raymond. An American Prophet Speaks. National Guardian, New York, NY., undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Schuman, Frederick L. The Devil and Jimmy Byrnes. Soviet Russia Today, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1948 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Stenographer's Report of the Seligman vs. Waton Debate. Marx-Engels Institute, New York, NY., 1922 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - U.S.A. Welcomes Soviet Farmers: The Dramatic Record of a History-Making Tour. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY., undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Why Soviet Russia Should Be Recognized. Friends of the Soviet Union, New York, NY., undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
- U.S.S.R.: Women I (13 pamphlets and an article) (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Bloor, Ella Reeve. Women in the Soviet Union. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1938 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Krupskaya, N. K. Soviet Woman: A Citizen with Equal Rights. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow. (2 copies), 1937 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Maurer, Rose. Soviet Women. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Nurina, F. Women in the Soviet Union. International Publishers, New York, NY., 1934 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Sibiriak, V. The Working Woman in the Soviet Union. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow. (2 copies), 1932 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Soviet Women to the Women of the World. American Council on Soviet Relations, New York, NY., undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
- U.S.S.R.: Women II (12 pamphlets) (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Cement the Unity of the Women in the Struggle for Peace and Progress. Union of Soviet Societies Friendship and Cultural with Foreign Countries, The Soviet Women's Committee, Moscow., 1963 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Friedrich, G. Miss U.S.S.R.: The Story of a Girl Stakhonovite. International Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Gorshenin, K. P. Soviet Women Enjoy Equal Civil Rights with Men. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1956 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - King, Beatrice. Women in Post-War Russia. British-Soviet Society, London., 1947 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Krupskaya, N. K. Soviet Woman: A Citizen with Equal Rights. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1937 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Razumova, Anna. Russian Women in the Building of Socialism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Vinogradova, Olga. Soviet Women. Soviet News, London., 1953 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Work Among Women. Communist Party of Great Britain, London. (2 copies), 1924 (Box 114, Folder 2)
- U.S.S.R.: Workers (14 pamphlets) (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Continuous Working Week. Friends of the Soviet Union, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Dimitrov, G. The Soviet Union and the Working Class of the Capitalist Countries. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1937 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Dyunin, Victor. How the USSR Found Work for All. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1980 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Dyunin, Viktor. Full Employment: How it Was Achieved. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1978 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Englestein, David and Carl Hirsch. A Tale of Two Workers. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1949 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Reznik, M. The Experiences of a Soviet Efficiency Expert. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1931 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Szumski, Romuald. Labor and the Soviet System. National Committee for a Free Europe, Inc., New York, NY., undated (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Weinberg, S. An American Worker in a Moscow Factory. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., 1933 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Where Miners Are Honored: Report of a Miners' Delegation to the USSR. SRT Publications Inc., New York, NY., 1950 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Yunga. The Life of a Soviet Seaman. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the U.S.S.R., Moscow., undated (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Zaslavsky, D. Where the Workers Are in Power. Co-operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the USSR, Moscow., 1931 (Box 114, Folder 3)
- U.S.S.R.: WWII I (25 pamphlets) (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Bessie, Alvah. The Soviet People at War. American Council on Soviet Relations, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Davies, Joseph E. Our Debt to Our Soviet Ally. Soviet Russia Today, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Dutt, R. Palme. Turning Point for the World. New York State Committee, Communist Party, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Fields, J. Behind the War-Head Lines. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Foster, William Z. Soviet Democracy and the War. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1943 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Hitler's Slave Markets. Soviet Russia Today, New York, NY., undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Lamont, Corliss. Soviet Russia and the Post-War World. National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc. (2 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Minor, Robert. Our Ally the Soviet Union. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1942 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Molotov, V. M. The Meaning of the Soviet-German Non-Aggression Pact. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - The U.S.S.R. at War: 50 Questions - 50 Answers. American Russian Institute for Cultural Relations with the Soviet Union, Inc., New York, NY. (2 copies), 1942 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Zaslavsky, D. The Face of Hitler's Army. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1943 (Box 114, Folder 4)
- U.S.S.R.: WWII II (19 pamphlets as well as an article and a supplement to "Northern Neighbors") (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Beloborodov, A. They Did Not Pass. Progress Publishers, Moscow., 1970 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Byrne, Norman. Soviet Strength and Soviet Strategy. American People's Mobilization, Los Angeles, CA., undated (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Clark, Joseph. Who Wants War? How the Soviet Union Builds for Peace. New Century Publishers, New York, NY., 1951 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Gershberg, S. Soviet Economy on a War Footing. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1943 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Grossman, Vassili. Stalingrad Hits Back. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1942 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Kalinin, M. The Patriotic War of the Soviet People Against the German Invaders. Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow., 1942 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Kournakoff, Sergei. What Russia Did for Victory. New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1945 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Krieger, Evgeni. Battle on the Volga., undated (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Lamont, Corliss. Soviet Russia versus Nazi Germany. American Council on Soviet Relations, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 114, Folder 5)